westernunion.co.uk 2013-07-27

# Online Privacy Statement | Western Union

Data Controllers

**All services except MyWU Programme** | **Western Union International Bank GmbH**  
---|---  
**MyWU Programme** | **Western Union Payment Service Ireland Limited**  
  
Effective Date: May 21 2013

This Online Privacy Statement describes how Western Union collects and uses your personal information ( **“Information”** ) that we obtain when you visit and/or use our website in the European Economic Area.

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

Western Union collects Information about you from a variety of sources, including but not limited to those listed below. You consent to the collection, transfer and storage of this Information by computers or other transfer or storage devices in the European Economic Area as well as elsewhere when you supply it, including the transfer and retention of your data outside the European Economic Area to countries, including but not limited to the United States, whose laws on holding personal data may be less stringent.

  * We collect Information that you supply when: (a) you ask us or one of our affiliated companies, Western Union agents or suppliers (“ **Affiliates** ”) to send or receive money or to provide other goods or services; (b) you submit Information on applications or other forms to us or our Affiliates; or (c) you otherwise submit Information to us, our Affiliates or others; 
  * We collect Information about your transactions with us, our Affiliates or others;
  * We collect Information about you from a variety of third party sources such as our business customers, government agencies and consumer and credit reporting agencies and other suppliers of public information,;
  * We collect Information about the domain and host from which you access the Internet; your computer’s Internet address; the browser and operating system software that you use; the date and time when you access our website and the Internet address of the site from which you linked to our website when you visit us;
  * We may collect and retain your bank card details for use in future transactions; and
  * We collect Information on your online activity as described in the paragraph below titled “ **COOKIES AND INTERNET TECHNOLOGY.** ”

The information we collect includes name, address, and telephone number, information about the form of identification used to send or receive a transaction (required by law in some instances and used by Western Union to prevent fraud), transaction activity and your computer’s internet address.

**USE OF INFORMATION**

At Western Union, we use the information that we obtain about our customers for the following activities

  * To provide, deliver and assist us in providing and delivering any products and services to you (including money transfers, loyalty programmes and other products or services) and to help us to improve and develop these services;
  * To send you and keep you informed about commercial communications, subject to any choices you have made, about Western Union or third party products and services, loyalty programmes or other updates
  * To verify any of the information that you provide in order to effect, administer and enforce transactions, to manage our customer relationships, to provide the requested products and services, to sign up agents, to ensure your eligibility for any services, or products you apply for, and to maintain the accuracy of our records;
  * To comply with legal obligations including those aimed at preventing money laundering regulations
  * To allow you to move between web pages during your visit without having to re-enter your password;
  * To store your preferences and other information and to track activity on our website;
  * To better understand the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns;
  * To determine whether you came to our site from a banner ad or an affiliate website;
  * To deliver Information specific to your interests on additional websites;
  * To determine whether you've acted on our promotional messages; and
  * To improve the running of this site and to improve the customer experience and the running of our business.

**COOKIES & INTERNET TECHNOLOGY**

We use internet technologies like cookies and Web beacons for a variety of purposes, including, but not limited to, those identified below.

  * To assist us in providing services to you;
  * To allow you to move between web pages during your visit without having to re-enter your password;
  * To temporarily track activity on our website;
  * To determine whether you came to our site from a banner ad or an Affiliate website;
  * To deliver Information specific to your interests on additional websites; or
  * To identify you when you visit the website, to personalise the content of the website for you and to assist you in carrying out transactions and accessing account information.
  * To determine whether you've acted on our promotional messages

Western Union has implemented the capability for the user to manage cookies on our websites. We will only read or write cookies based on your preference level **(note: cookies set prior to you changing your preference level are maintained on your computer; to remove them please refer to your browser settings)**. If your browser does not support JavaScript, you can find out about the cookies used on our sites and can only manage the use of cookies through your web browser settings. Please note that if you disable all cookies on your browser, this will limit the features of this site and may have an impact on the ability to complete your transaction.

**[Click here](javascript:window.scrollTo\(0,0\);showCookieOptInOptions\(\);)to manage your cookies**

**For more information on how Western Union uses cookiesclick here**

**INFORMATION WE DISCLOSE**

Subject to your consent or as otherwise permitted by law, we may disclose the Information we collect in the paragraphs titled, **"INFORMATION WE COLLECT"** and **"COOKIES AND INTERNET TECHNOLOGY"** to our Affiliates and to unaffiliated third parties as described below for any of the purposes described in the statement, including those described in the paragraph entitled **“USE OF INFORMATION”**.

We may disclose Information to any Western Union Affiliate to effect, administer and complete transactions or deliver products or services including, but not limited to:

  * Western Union group companies including but not limited to Western Union International Limited; Western Union Financial Services Inc; Western Union Payment Services Ireland Limited; Western Union Payment Services UK Limited.
  * Companies which help us to run or improve the running of our business or which help us to deliver products and services to you and to banks, credit card companies and credit reference agencies,
  * In order to comply with legal, regulatory, security and processing requirements, government and foreign government requirements applicable to us, our Affiliates or service providers, including but not limited to anti-money laundering laws;
  * To organisations which help us to process transactions, validate customer information and help us to prevent debt, fraud theft or loss;
  * As permitted or required by law

We may disclose Information about current and former customers to perform marketing, business analysis and advertising services to companies with whom we have contractual or joint marketing arrangements upon notice that you have provided unambiguous consent (opt-in) for the use of Information for these purposes.

**CONFIDENTIALITY AND SECURITY**

We endeavour to maintain physical, technical and procedural safeguards that comply with applicable government laws and regulations to guard your Information. We also endeavour to restrict Information access to our employees, agents and representatives who need to know it. Despite our efforts, and as you probably know, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions sent to us or may wrongly instruct you to disclose Information to them while posing as Western Union.

**PERSONAL CHOICE**

Where you have provided us with your consent to use, store or disclose your Information, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time by using the contact details below. If you do withdraw your consent, we will cease using that Information unless we are required to continue to do so by law.

Western Union maintains your choice and transaction history based on our record retention policies. If you do not perform another transaction within the retention time period, your Information, as well as your choice, will be removed.

**ACCURACY OF INFORMATION**

You may request (by contacting us in the manner set out below) details of the Information that we hold and request us to correct or erase any erroneous or out-of-date Information. We reserve the right to independently verify claims made. To protect your privacy, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before making providing details or corrections. Where permitted by law, we reserve the right to assess a service charge for providing you with any information in connection with your request.

**EXTERNAL WEB SITES**

Western Union’s website may be linked to or from third party websites. Western Union is not responsible for the content or privacy practices employed by websites that are linked to or from our website.

**CHANGES**

Western Union reserves the right to modify this Privacy Statement. Updated Privacy Statements will be posted at this website when amendments occur. We urge you to review this Privacy Statement when you visit to obtain the most current statement. You may change your choices at any time.

**CONTACT US**

If you have any questions or queries, please **contact us**.
